<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
 <channel>
  <title> - computers</title>
  <description>Posts tagged as 'computers'</description>
  <atom:link href="http://hunleyd.github.io/feed.computers.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
  <link>http://hunleyd.github.io/tag/computers/</link>
  <updated>2016-12-03T17:00:40-05:00</updated>
  <author>
   <name></name>
   <email></email>
  </author>

  
   <item>
    <title>Routing email through GMail on OSX</title>
    <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.postfix.org/mysza.gif&quot; border=0 align=left style=&quot;PADDING-RIGHT: 5px&quot;&gt;Like most geeks, I have scripts that I&amp;#39;ve written that I like to have run from cron on a regular basis. And since the running of these scripts might be in the middle of the night, I like for them to email their output to me so I know if they succeeded or failed. As such, I need an MTA on my computer that can actually deliver these emails to GMail. For me, this is trivial using Sendmail or SSMTP on a Linux box, but I can never remember how to do this using Postfix on OSX. So after having to Google everything to get this running once more, I&amp;#39;m going to commit the steps here for my future self to reference :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first thing we&amp;#39;re going to do is open an iTerm and &lt;code&gt;sudo -i&lt;/code&gt; to become root. Then we&amp;#39;re going to &lt;code&gt;vi /etc/postfix/main.cf&lt;/code&gt; and we&amp;#39;re going to add/set the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-conf&quot; data-lang=&quot;conf&quot;&gt;myhostname = smtp.gmail.com
relayhost = [smtp.gmail.com]:587
smtp_sasl_auth_enable = yes
smtp_sasl_password_maps= hash:/etc/postfix/sasl_passwd
smtp_sasl_security_options = noanonymous
smtp_sasl_mechanism_filter = plain
smtp_use_tls = yes
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have Two-Factor Auth (2FA) enabled on my Google account (you should too!), so for me, the next step is to log into Google and create an &amp;#39;app password&amp;#39;. Once I have that password in hand, we &lt;code&gt;vi /etc/postfix/sasl_passwd&lt;/code&gt; and add:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-conf&quot; data-lang=&quot;conf&quot;&gt;[smtp.gmail.com]:587 username@gmail.com:app_passwd
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Secure that file by running &lt;code&gt;chmod 0600 /etc/postfix/sasl_passwd&lt;/code&gt; and then have Postfix hash it by doing &lt;code&gt;postmap /etc/postfix/sasl_passwd&lt;/code&gt;. Finally, restart Postfix:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot; data-lang=&quot;bash&quot;&gt;launchctl stop org.postfix.master
launchctl start org.postfix.master
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And everything should work.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    <link>http://hunleyd.github.io/Routing-email-through-GMail-on-OSX/ </link>
    <pubDate>2016-11-15T05:51:00-05:00</pubDate>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">http://hunleyd.github.io/Routing-email-through-GMail-on-OSX/</guid>
   </item>
  
   <item>
    <title>Glutton for Punishment</title>
    <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.theshell.guru/wp-content/uploads/2015/12/osx-logo3.png&quot; border=0 align=right&gt;I recently got a new Macbook Pro from work as my old one was having keyboard issues and since it was 3+ yrs old they deemed it not worth fixing. As you probably know, I spent a lot of time and effort on the previous mbp to get &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gentoo.org&quot;&gt;Gentoo&lt;/a&gt; up and running on it. I chose &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; to do so with this one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I have looked into it and believe that I could get Gentoo up and running fairly easily, I&amp;#39;ve decided to skip it for now and try to live with OSX. I travel for work and never know what I&amp;#39;m going to be asked to do when onsite. Sometimes I have to present things on a projector while other times the customer only has 5Ghz wifi available. And thanks to the proprietary nature of these machines, these features are either non-functional or sub-optimal under Linux. I&amp;#39;m also getting tired of our IT staff telling me Linux isn&amp;#39;t supported whenever I have an issue, even if that issue clearly doesn&amp;#39;t have anything to do with the OS. And several other minor annoyances that have added up over my three yrs tenure here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, yeah. I&amp;#39;ve decided to sign up for the pain of staying in OSX. So far, I think I&amp;#39;ve managed to coerce the system into a &amp;#39;feel-alike&amp;#39; of my prior KDE 5 Plasma environment but it&amp;#39;s taken a lot of tweaking and Googling and setting of magic CLI commands to get OSX to do my bidding. And I&amp;#39;ve had to buy more than a few apps to get functionality that I got for free on Linux, which chaps my ass.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So we&amp;#39;ll see how this lasts. Or doesn&amp;#39;t.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    <link>http://hunleyd.github.io/Glutton-for-punishment/ </link>
    <pubDate>2016-02-29T05:14:50-05:00</pubDate>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">http://hunleyd.github.io/Glutton-for-punishment/</guid>
   </item>
  
 </channel>
</rss>
