<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

 <title></title>
 <link href="http://hunleyd.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://hunleyd.github.io/"/>
 <updated>2016-01-25T12:53:23-05:00</updated>
 <id>http://hunleyd.github.io</id>
 <author>
   <name></name>
   <email></email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>Efficient, yet Creepy</title>
   <link href="http://hunleyd.github.io/Efficient-Yet-Creepy/"/>
   <updated>2016-01-21T13:30:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://hunleyd.github.io/Efficient-Yet-Creepy</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;So I&amp;#39;m sitting here seting up a new Internet connected device I bought recently (more on it later) and I can&amp;#39;t seem to get it to setup properly. I can create an account on their site, I can login to said account, I can power on said device and connect to it using the app and configure it to use my home wifi, but the device just won&amp;#39;t ever finish connecting and syncing w/ my account on the site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I try this about half a dozen times, with a few reboots and even a reset of the device in there. Still no luck. So I power it off, set it aside, and go do some things IRL thinking &amp;quot;I&amp;#39;ll come back to it&amp;quot;. Not five minutes later, I get an email on my phone from Tech Support at the device&amp;#39;s company saying thusly:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We noticed that you are having problems adding $device to your system.
To assist you with the process, we would like to first push a firmware
update to your $device. Please keep your $device plugged in and we
will take care of the rest. We will send you another email when you
have been updated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now &lt;em&gt;that&amp;#39;s&lt;/em&gt; efficient. And &lt;strong&gt;super creepy&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I kinda like it :D&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Huawei Watch Review</title>
   <link href="http://hunleyd.github.io/Huawei-Watch-Review/"/>
   <updated>2016-01-21T12:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://hunleyd.github.io/Huawei-Watch-Review</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gethuawei.com/buy-huawei-watch&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.gethuawei.com/media/wysiwyg/pdpcms/huawei_watch/watches/stainless-leather1.png&quot; width=150 height=197 border=0 align=left&gt;&lt;/a&gt;A couple of my mates wanted me to let them know what I thought of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.huawei.com/en/&quot;&gt;Huawei&lt;/a&gt; Watch (hereafter, &amp;#39;H&amp;#39;) after upgrading from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.motorola.com/us/products/moto-360&quot;&gt;Moto 360&lt;/a&gt; (hereafter, 360) and spending some time getting to know the &amp;#39;H&amp;#39;. So here&amp;#39;s my thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TL;DR&lt;/strong&gt; Better than the 360 in every way that counts&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I should probably preface this review by saying that I loved (and still love) the 360. I was excited to buy it, I was excited to see it ship to my house, I was pissed that I wasn&amp;#39;t at my house when it arrived (long-term gig in LA), I was proud to wear it, and I loved showing it to anyone who cared (and probably more than a few who didn&amp;#39;t). Having said that, the 360 I had was a Gen 1 in every sense. It was the first watch Moto had made. It was the first smartwatch Moto had made. It was the flagship Android Wear device. And the minute I got my hands on a 2&lt;sup&gt;nd&lt;/sup&gt; gen device, those things were readily apparent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;#39;t get me wrong. It&amp;#39;s not all sunshine and roses w/ the &amp;#39;H&amp;#39;. For example, charging is actually quite a bit of a sorrier state than with the 360. You see, the 360 has a standard Qi charging mechanism. So while there is a cute little official charging stand, you can make do with &lt;em&gt;any&lt;/em&gt; Qi charger you have once you figure out where to place the watch on the coil. And the official charger uses a standard, I-have-tons-of-them-all-of-the-place USB-A to USB-micro cable. The &amp;#39;H&amp;#39;, on the other hand, uses pogo pins to connect to it&amp;#39;s charger. Which means you &lt;u&gt;have&lt;/u&gt; to use a compatible charger (of which there is only one currently). Take a road trip and forget your charger? Buy another one or go without your watch. And to add to the insult, the charger cable, while having a standard USB-A plug on one end, is terminated inside the charging puck. So if the cord should go bad or isn&amp;#39;t long enough, too bad. You can&amp;#39;t use one of those USB cables from the pile in your desk drawer. Nope. Sorry. And then, of course, there&amp;#39;s the &lt;em&gt;act&lt;/em&gt; of charging the watch. With the 360, you simply slide it into its dock, and you&amp;#39;re done. Heck, after a while, you can almost lightly toss it into the charger like a game of corn hole and it will charge. Half asleep? Drunk? No problem. Tis easy. The &amp;#39;H&amp;#39; on the other hand? You have to line up the pogos &lt;b&gt;exactly&lt;/b&gt; or you aren&amp;#39;t getting any juice. And I mean exact. Doesn&amp;#39;t matter if the watch and the charger look perfectly aligned and centered with each other. If the pins aren&amp;#39;t perfect, no juice for you! I&amp;#39;ve already had my share of waking up to find out the watch didn&amp;#39;t charge. It SUCKS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Pro tip: I&amp;#39;ve found that hovering the &amp;#39;H&amp;#39; right over the charging puck allows the magnets in them to pull them together in such a way that the puck &amp;quot;leaps&amp;quot; up and attaches to the watch with the pogo pins perfectly positioned&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So yeah, charging. The one thorn in the rose. But worth it, imho.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Review: ★★★★★&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>I Have The Power</title>
   <link href="http://hunleyd.github.io/I-Have-The-Power/"/>
   <updated>2016-01-16T19:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://hunleyd.github.io/I-Have-The-Power</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.snappower.com/snaprays-guidelight/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.snappower.com/wp-content/themes/enfold-child/images/guidelight_review.jpg&quot; border=0 align=left height=262 width=262&gt;&lt;/a&gt;A while back, I ran across a little project on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kickstarter.com&quot;&gt;Kickstarter&lt;/a&gt; from a company called &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.snappower.com&quot;&gt;SnapPower&lt;/a&gt;. The project was for a product called Guidelights.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, I&amp;#39;m a &amp;quot;big boy&amp;quot; and don&amp;#39;t need a night light, but I do wander around the house after dark quite a bit and hate turning on the lights when I&amp;#39;m in a room for like a whole minute. So The concept of having LED lights embedded into the outlet cover and having them turn on/off based on the ambient light in the room sounded pretty cool. And the fact that there&amp;#39;s no wiring or anything was slick. So I ponied up and ordered some.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I gotta tell you, they rock! I now have one in the upstairs hallyway, another at the bottom of the stairs, and a third on the island in the kitchen. It&amp;#39;s freaking perfect. Seriously. And like I said, there&amp;#39;s &lt;em&gt;no skill involved&lt;/em&gt;. If you can work a flat head screwdriver, you can install these!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In fact, when Stephanie movies into her apartment (soonish), I&amp;#39;ll be outfitting her place with a few of these as well. They&amp;#39;re really that good,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Review: ★★★★★&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.snappower.com/snappower-chargers/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.snappower.com/wp-content/themes/enfold-child/images/charger_review.jpg&quot; border=0 align=left height=262 width=262&gt;&lt;/a&gt;As much as I love the guidelights, I was stoked when SnapPower announced their Snap Power Chargers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;#39;t know what it&amp;#39;s like in your household, but all four of us have smart phones, three of us have tablets, and two of us have smart watches. Someone &lt;em&gt;always&lt;/em&gt; needs to charge something. And my family is &lt;strong&gt;horrible&lt;/strong&gt; about removing their chargers from outlets when they&amp;#39;re done. And one person in particular has taken to unplugging whatever is &amp;quot;in the way&amp;quot; so she can charge her phone close to wherever she&amp;#39;s sitting! Clearly, a solution that adds USB ports and frees up electrical outlets is a solution I need to have.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I eagerly bought &lt;em&gt;five&lt;/em&gt; of these things. I installed all but one yesterday, and I gotta say it is as good of an investment as the light covers. I will be installing a few of these in Steph&amp;#39;s apartment also. Now, I&amp;#39;ll grant you that they are not &amp;quot;quick charge&amp;quot;. And there&amp;#39;s only one USB facing the right side of the cover instead of one on both the left and right. But I understand there&amp;#39;s only so much room in these things, and only so much power you can leech off the contacts. So I&amp;#39;m not terribly upset. It would be nice though if you could choose left or right when ordering.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Honestly, I&amp;#39;m kinda stoked to see what this company comes up with next. Of all the random crap I&amp;#39;ve backed on Kickstarter, SnapPower is easily the most useful and easiest to recommend to others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Review: ★★★★✩&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>More Bloggy Goodness</title>
   <link href="http://hunleyd.github.io/More-Bloggy-Goodness/"/>
   <updated>2016-01-15T20:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://hunleyd.github.io/More-Bloggy-Goodness</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s been a bit of a busy day for me and my blog. I&amp;#39;ve added:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;an RSS feed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;an archive&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;tags&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Disqus comments&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All with as little effort on my part as I&amp;#39;ve &lt;em&gt;ever&lt;/em&gt; put into a blog. I &lt;strong&gt;fucking&lt;/strong&gt; love this blogging platform!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Once More, With Feeling</title>
   <link href="http://hunleyd.github.io/Once-More-With-Feeling/"/>
   <updated>2016-01-15T19:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://hunleyd.github.io/Once-More-With-Feeling</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the new blog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;#39;s right, I&amp;#39;m running my own blog &lt;em&gt;once again&lt;/em&gt;. I know, I know. It&amp;#39;s been a while. And I&amp;#39;ve picked &lt;em&gt;yet another&lt;/em&gt; platform for hosting my blog. But you know what? You&amp;#39;re just going to have to suck it up. I&amp;#39;ve been itching to make some new posts for a while now, and the platforms at my disposal, &lt;em&gt;cough&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;G+&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;cough&lt;/em&gt;, just haven&amp;#39;t really cut it. Sure, they sorta worked, but with the recent direction that platform is headed? Forget it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So then a coworker mentioned standing up &lt;em&gt;his&lt;/em&gt; new blog using &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.github.com&quot;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt; and I was blown away at how it worked. It just &lt;em&gt;so totally fit&lt;/em&gt; with my workflow and preferences. So here we are. Everything old is new again. Or something.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.wired.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/08/poster.jpg&quot; border=0 alt=&quot;Yeah, it&#39;s that kinda blog&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 

</feed>
