<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed/by_tag/android.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-08-25T16:20:30-04:00</updated><id>/feed/by_tag/android.xml</id><title type="html">Doug’s Dabblings</title><subtitle>A collection of thoughts on things in my life that I&apos;m experiencing, playing with, or suffering through. Mostly tech related, but sometimes not.</subtitle><author><name>Douglas J Hunley</name><email>doug.hunley@gmail.com</email></author><entry><title type="html">Mi Box</title><link href="/2016/11/02/Mi-Box/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Mi Box" /><published>2016-11-02T06:27:55-04:00</published><updated>2016-11-02T06:27:55-04:00</updated><id>/2016/11/02/Mi-Box</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2016/11/02/Mi-Box/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i5.walmartimages.com/asr/a45c44b3-a6fc-465e-8231-16f42efc6347_1.474cf868352361552e656c2cfec1f962.jpeg&quot; class=&quot;lleader&quot; /&gt;I’m a fan of Android TV. While I didn’t blog about it, I ran out and bought a Nexus Player on day 1. And I loved it! OK, I loved it &lt;em&gt;more&lt;/em&gt; after the upgrade to Android 6.x, but still.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, now I’ve upgraded from the Nexus Player to the Mi Box. It’s a bit of a risk, since no one knows the upgrade history for Xiaomi, but I’m OK with that. Especially at a mere $70 for this thing. As much as I loved the Player, I am enjoying this device &lt;em&gt;so much more&lt;/em&gt;. It’s stupid fast, the remote is so much better, and I feel like I get a better picture out of it (which is silly, I don’t have a 4k TV so it should be the same 1080p HD picture I got from the Player).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This tiny little box (101 x 101 x 19.5mm) comes with an Amlogic Quad-core Cortex-A53 processor running at 2.0GHz, a Mali 450 GPU running at 750MHz, 2GB of ram, and 8GB of storage. On the back is an HDMI port, a headphone jack (why?), a power adaptor port (sadly, not a standard USB-C or MicroUSB), a single USB 2.0 port. It’s pretty sparse port wise, but really that’s all you need. There’s a subtly white LED on the very front of the device to show you that it’s powered on too. Otherwise, it’s just a sleek little black hockey puck sitting in my entertainment center.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, I’m so pleased with this little thing that I convinced Stephanie to buy one, gave my Player to Tina, and I’m considering buying one of these for Emily when she moves out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Review: ★★★★☆&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Douglas J Hunley</name><email>doug.hunley@gmail.com</email></author><category term="android" /><category term="review" /><summary type="html">I’m a fan of Android TV. While I didn’t blog about it, I ran out and bought a Nexus Player on day 1. And I loved it! OK, I loved it more after the upgrade to Android 6.x, but still.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Smart Lock on Android N DP2</title><link href="/2016/04/24/Smart-Lock-on-Android-N-DP2/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Smart Lock on Android N DP2" /><published>2016-04-24T18:18:56-04:00</published><updated>2016-04-24T18:18:56-04:00</updated><id>/2016/04/24/Smart-Lock-on-Android-N-DP2</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2016/04/24/Smart-Lock-on-Android-N-DP2/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://pre13.deviantart.net/ba29/th/pre/i/2016/070/a/f/android_n_logo_by_stayka007-d9untw2.png&quot; class=&quot;rleader&quot; /&gt;As mentioned in my previous &lt;a href=&quot;/Now-on-Tap-Android-N-DP2/&quot;&gt;post&lt;/a&gt; I’ve stumbled across two issues with the 2&lt;sup&gt;nd&lt;/sup&gt; Developer Preview of Android N. The latter of these issues is discussed here. For reasons I won’t get into, I had need to wipe and reset my Huawei Watch, and after doing so I attempted to setup Smart Lock such that when the watch was connected, the phone would stay unlocked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was immediately aware of &lt;em&gt;some&lt;/em&gt; kind of issue since the phone didn’t prompt me to setup Smaet Lock after pairing the watch. So I went into the Android Settings app, then Security, and went to tap on Smart Lock only to find it &lt;em&gt;gone&lt;/em&gt;. Thinking maybe Google had moved it somewherre else, I used the new ‘search Settings’ feature and searched for Smart Lock, Lock, and Smart. None of them tuened up what I was looking for! After some Googling, I had enough clues to figure out what had happened to the option and how to restore it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To restore Smart Lock to the Security tab of the Settings app, do this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;open the Android Settings app&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;tap Security&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;scroll down to the Advanced section&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;tap Trust Agents&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;toggle Smart Lock (Google)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, when ypou back button to the Security settings, the Smart Lock option will be restored and function like before. I dont know wtf ‘unset’ it as a Trust Agent provider in DP2 or why, but there you go.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Douglas J Hunley</name><email>doug.hunley@gmail.com</email></author><category term="android" /><category term="nexus5x" /><category term="protip" /><summary type="html">As mentioned in my previous post I’ve stumbled across two issues with the 2nd Developer Preview of Android N. The latter of these issues is discussed here. For reasons I won’t get into, I had need to wipe and reset my Huawei Watch, and after doing so I attempted to setup Smart Lock such that when the watch was connected, the phone would stay unlocked.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Now on Tap on Android N DP2</title><link href="/2016/04/24/Now-on-Tap-Android-N-DP2/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Now on Tap on Android N DP2" /><published>2016-04-24T17:53:06-04:00</published><updated>2016-04-24T17:53:06-04:00</updated><id>/2016/04/24/Now-on-Tap-Android-N-DP2</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2016/04/24/Now-on-Tap-Android-N-DP2/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://pre13.deviantart.net/ba29/th/pre/i/2016/070/a/f/android_n_logo_by_stayka007-d9untw2.png&quot; class=&quot;lleader&quot; /&gt;Like any good geek, I jumped at the opportunity to enroll my Nexus 5x into the Android N Beta Program. And for the most part, it’s worked really well for me. I &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; like Android N so far and can’t wait for the final release. However, after updating from Developer Preview 1 (DP1) to Developer Preview 2 (DP2) via OTA, I noticed two small issues. The first issue is that I could not, for the life of me, get Now On Tap to enable even though it was previously enabled on DP1.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m happy to report that I figured out, and I thought I’d share it in case anyone else has run this issue and was stumped. Just to be clear, if you open the Google app, then go into Settings, and then into Now on Tap, there’s a toggle. Simply flipping it is &lt;em&gt;supposed&lt;/em&gt; to be enough to turn it on. But in my case, the toggle would &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; flip on. It was permanently flipped to off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To fix this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;head into the Android Settings app&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;touch Apps&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;touch the gear icon on the top right corner&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;touch Assist &amp;amp; voice input&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;touch Assist App&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;chose Google&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you’ve done this, you’ll find that you can enable Now on Tap through the normal toggle.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Douglas J Hunley</name><email>doug.hunley@gmail.com</email></author><category term="android" /><category term="nexus5x" /><category term="protip" /><summary type="html">Like any good geek, I jumped at the opportunity to enroll my Nexus 5x into the Android N Beta Program. And for the most part, it’s worked really well for me. I really like Android N so far and can’t wait for the final release. However, after updating from Developer Preview 1 (DP1) to Developer Preview 2 (DP2) via OTA, I noticed two small issues. The first issue is that I could not, for the life of me, get Now On Tap to enable even though it was previously enabled on DP1.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Huawei Watch Review</title><link href="/2016/01/21/Huawei-Watch-Review/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Huawei Watch Review" /><published>2016-01-21T12:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2016-01-21T12:00:00-05:00</updated><id>/2016/01/21/Huawei-Watch-Review</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2016/01/21/Huawei-Watch-Review/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gethuawei.com/buy-huawei-watch&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.androidpolice.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/09/nexus2cee_DSC09617-728x485.jpg&quot; class=&quot;lleader&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;A couple of my mates wanted me to let them know what I thought of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.huawei.com/en/&quot;&gt;Huawei&lt;/a&gt; Watch (hereafter, ‘H’) after upgrading from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.motorola.com/us/products/moto-360&quot;&gt;Moto 360&lt;/a&gt; (hereafter, 360) and spending some time getting to know the ‘H’. So here’s my thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TL;DR&lt;/strong&gt; Better than the 360 in every way that counts&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I should probably preface this review by saying that I loved (and still love) the 360. I was excited to buy it, I was excited to see it ship to my house, I was pissed that I wasn’t at my house when it arrived (long-term gig in LA), I was proud to wear it, and I loved showing it to anyone who cared (and probably more than a few who didn’t). Having said that, the 360 I had was a Gen 1 in every sense. It was the first watch Moto had made. It was the first smartwatch Moto had made. It was the flagship Android Wear device. And the minute I got my hands on a 2&lt;sup&gt;nd&lt;/sup&gt; gen device, those things were readily apparent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t get me wrong. It’s not all sunshine and roses w/ the ‘H’. For example, charging is actually quite a bit of a sorrier state than with the 360. You see, the 360 has a standard Qi charging mechanism. So while there is a cute little official charging stand, you can make do with &lt;em&gt;any&lt;/em&gt; Qi charger you have once you figure out where to place the watch on the coil. And the official charger uses a standard, I-have-tons-of-them-all-of-the-place USB-A to USB-micro cable. The ‘H’, on the other hand, uses pogo pins to connect to it’s charger. Which means you &lt;u&gt;have&lt;/u&gt; to use a compatible charger (of which there is only one currently). Take a road trip and forget your charger? Buy another one or go without your watch. And to add to the insult, the charger cable, while having a standard USB-A plug on one end, is terminated inside the charging puck. So if the cord should go bad or isn’t long enough, too bad. You can’t use one of those USB cables from the pile in your desk drawer. Nope. Sorry. And then, of course, there’s the &lt;em&gt;act&lt;/em&gt; of charging the watch. With the 360, you simply slide it into its dock, and you’re done. Heck, after a while, you can almost lightly toss it into the charger like a game of corn hole and it will charge. Half asleep? Drunk? No problem. Tis easy. The ‘H’ on the other hand? You have to line up the pogos &lt;b&gt;exactly&lt;/b&gt; or you aren’t getting any juice. And I mean exact. Doesn’t matter if the watch and the charger look perfectly aligned and centered with each other. If the pins aren’t perfect, no juice for you! I’ve already had my share of waking up to find out the watch didn’t charge. It SUCKS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Pro tip: I’ve found that hovering the ‘H’ right over the charging puck allows the magnets in them to pull them together in such a way that the puck “leaps” up and attaches to the watch with the pogo pins perfectly positioned&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So yeah, charging. The one thorn in the rose. But worth it, imho.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Review: ★★★★★&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Douglas J Hunley</name><email>doug.hunley@gmail.com</email></author><category term="android" /><category term="review" /><category term="geek" /><summary type="html">A couple of my mates wanted me to let them know what I thought of the Huawei Watch (hereafter, ‘H’) after upgrading from the Moto 360 (hereafter, 360) and spending some time getting to know the ‘H’. So here’s my thoughts.</summary></entry></feed>