<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed/by_tag/gaming.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-08-16T14:59:18-04:00</updated><id>/feed/by_tag/gaming.xml</id><title type="html">Doug’s Dabblings</title><subtitle>A collection of thoughts on things in my life that I&apos;m experiencing, playing with, or suffering through. Mostly tech related, but sometimes not.</subtitle><author><name>Douglas J Hunley</name><email>doug.hunley@gmail.com</email></author><entry><title type="html">Welcome to Cypheri</title><link href="/2016/10/01/Welcome-to-Cypheri/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welcome to Cypheri" /><published>2016-10-01T07:23:56-04:00</published><updated>2016-10-01T07:23:56-04:00</updated><id>/2016/10/01/Welcome-to-Cypheri</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2016/10/01/Welcome-to-Cypheri/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.nationstates.net/images/flags/uploads/cypheri__755901.jpg&quot; class=&quot;lleader&quot; /&gt;I recently discovered the online game &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nationstates.net&quot;&gt;NationStates&lt;/a&gt; thanks to a Reddit thread and was intrigued. So I logged in, created the nation of Cypheri and then used &lt;a href=&quot;https://blogtrottr.com&quot;&gt;BlogTrottr&lt;/a&gt; to feed the RSS feed into my inbox (which allows me offline play essentially. I ignore it until I get a notice). So far, it’s been a neat little experience. I’m pretty sure if you know me well enough to be reading this blog that I know you well enough to say you’ll enjoy it too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Without further ado, let me welcome you to the Republic of Cypheri, a left-leaning college state. Our motto is “strength through freedom”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Republic of Cypheri is a tiny, genial nation, renowned for its compulsory military service and irreverence towards religion. The compassionate population of 7 million Cypherians enjoy extensive civil freedoms, particularly in social issues, while business tends to be more regulated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The large government prioritizes Education, although Welfare, Defense, and Law &amp;amp; Order are also considered important, while Spirituality and Industry are ignored. The average income tax rate is 39.8%, but much higher for the wealthy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Cypherian economy, worth 251 billion dollars a year, is fairly diversified and led by the Tourism industry, with major contributions from Automobile Manufacturing, Basket Weaving, and Retail. State-owned companies are common. Average income is 35,928 dollars, and evenly distributed, with the richest citizens earning only 2.0 times as much as the poorest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for visiting, we hope you enjoyed your time here!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Douglas J Hunley</name><email>doug.hunley@gmail.com</email></author><category term="general" /><category term="gaming" /><summary type="html">I recently discovered the online game NationStates thanks to a Reddit thread and was intrigued. So I logged in, created the nation of Cypheri and then used BlogTrottr to feed the RSS feed into my inbox (which allows me offline play essentially. I ignore it until I get a notice). So far, it’s been a neat little experience. I’m pretty sure if you know me well enough to be reading this blog that I know you well enough to say you’ll enjoy it too.</summary></entry></feed>