<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed/by_tag/gentoo.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-07-26T13:09:36-04:00</updated><id>/feed/by_tag/gentoo.xml</id><title type="html">Douglas J Hunley</title><subtitle>It&apos;s not that I&apos;m anti-social; I&apos;m just not user-friendly</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Hello again old friend</title><link href="/posts/Hello-again-old-friend/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hello again old friend" /><published>2021-07-24T06:04:49-04:00</published><updated>2021-07-24T06:04:49-04:00</updated><id>/posts/Hello-again-old-friend</id><content type="html" xml:base="/posts/Hello-again-old-friend/">&lt;p&gt;I &lt;a href=&quot;/posts/Bye-Pi-Hello-NUC&quot;&gt;posted&lt;/a&gt; a year ago about dropping ClearLinux and
switching to Ubuntu Server on my NUC. While that little experiment was fun, it
didn’t last long. I’m not entirely sure what it is about my brain/personality, but
I just do not like any of the binary Linux distros out there for my own long-term use so I went back to my old friend, Gentoo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s been a few months now, and I must say that running Gentoo on the NUC has
been a pleasant experience. It took a little work to get up to speed on recent
changes in Gentoo, and I had to dig into things to get an optimized install
going on the NUC, but I’m pretty happy with the results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe I’ll actually blog more this time about what I’m doing with this
install. Or maybe I’ll lapse back into old habits and forget to. Only time
will tell.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="computers" /><category term="linux" /><category term="gentoo" /><summary type="html">I posted a year ago about dropping ClearLinux and switching to Ubuntu Server on my NUC. While that little experiment was fun, it didn’t last long. I’m not entirely sure what it is about my brain/personality, but I just do not like any of the binary Linux distros out there for my own long-term use so I went back to my old friend, Gentoo.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/%7B%22feature%22=%3E%22tech.jpg%22%7D" /><media:content medium="image" url="/%7B%22feature%22=%3E%22tech.jpg%22%7D" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>