<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.1.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed/by_tag/smarthome.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-07-19T14:30:36-04:00</updated><id>/feed/by_tag/smarthome.xml</id><title type="html">Douglas J Hunley</title><subtitle>It's not that I'm anti-social; I'm just not user-friendly</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Locking it down</title><link href="/posts/Locking-it-down/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Locking it down" /><published>2018-06-18T08:45:02-04:00</published><updated>2018-06-18T08:45:02-04:00</updated><id>/posts/Locking-it-down</id><content type="html" xml:base="/posts/Locking-it-down/">&lt;p&gt;I finally saved up and bought myself a smart lock at the end of April. I ended up getting the &lt;a href=&quot;https://smile.amazon.com/gp/product/B0752V8D8D&quot;&gt;August Smart Lock Pro&lt;/a&gt; with the Connect module. Now that I’ve used it for a month and a half, I feel like I can finally review it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;TL;DR I love this lock.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Honestly, the hardest part of this whole process was picking the lock to buy. I looked at the August lock, I looked at the Kwikset Bluetooth lock, I even looked at the Nest lock and debating waiting for its release. In the end, I chose the August for two reasons: it integrates with Google Home natively (no ‘talk to August’ bullshit) and it uses the existing lock’s keys so my landlord can’t complain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Installing the lock was stupid simple. You are directed to download their app for your phone, create an account, and then it gives you full-screen step-by-step directions. There’s nothing unusual about this deadlock, so if you’ve ever changed one before, you know how to do this. You’ll need a screwdriver and maybe 10 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Installation is basically 4 steps:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Remove the old back on the deadbolt&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Find the correct shaft adaptor&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Install the new August back&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Connect to the wifi&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t leave the house very often, if I’m honest, but the occasions I have since installing this have been very nice. I leave, the door locks (and thanks to other integrations my Blink cameras turn on); I return, the door unlocks (and the cameras turn off). I don’t have to carry a key with me. I don’t have to empty a hand to fish out my key to unlock the door. When I go to bed at night, I just tell Google to lock the door. The only minor annoyance is that Google won’t voice unlock the door (for security reasons).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve yet to use the app to give anyone a ‘temporary key’ but I have used the app to check on (and change) the lock status. I’ve also used the app to update the firmware on the lock.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re considering a smart lock, I highly recommend you look at the August Pro.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;★★★★★&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="geek" /><category term="smarthome" /><category term="review" /><summary type="html">I finally saved up and bought myself a smart lock at the end of April. I ended up getting the August Smart Lock Pro with the Connect module. Now that I’ve used it for a month and a half, I feel like I can finally review it.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/%7B%22feature%22=%3E%22review.jpg%22%7D" /><media:content medium="image" url="/%7B%22feature%22=%3E%22review.jpg%22%7D" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>