<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
 <channel>
  <title>Douglas J Hunley - general</title>
  <description>Posts tagged as 'general'</description>
  <atom:link href="/feeds/feed.general.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
  <link>/tags/#general/</link>
  <updated>2017-07-26T12:50:57-04:00</updated>
  <author>
   <name></name>
   <email></email>
  </author>

  
   <item>
    <title>When you cannot get there from here</title>
    <description>&lt;p&gt;Connecting to a PostgreSQL instance isn’t hard generally, but sometimes you can run into issues. Sometimes a port isn’t open on a firewall, or the server is in a VLAN that you can’t get to, or perhaps the server isn’t running on the network interface you think it is. More commonly, you can reach the PostgreSQL instance but you’re connection isn’t authorized (which is not the same as being unable to &lt;em&gt;authenticate&lt;/em&gt;). Fortunately, the error messages returned in these different failure scenarios are fairly verbose and distinct so you can easily tell which scenario you’re facing. Let’s dive into each scenario and see what the error looks like, shall we?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;scenario-1---bad-password&quot;&gt;Scenario 1 - Bad password&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s first assume that everything is working and you &lt;em&gt;can&lt;/em&gt; actually connect to the PostgreSQL instance, but you can’t authenticate. The error will look like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/authentication.png&quot; alt=&quot;auth failed&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you can see, the message makes it pretty clear that you were able to connect, but your credentials were wrong (you were &lt;em&gt;authorized&lt;/em&gt; to connect, but failed to &lt;em&gt;authenticate&lt;/em&gt;). Did you type the password incorrectly? Is there a &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;~/.pgpass&lt;/code&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.postgresql.org/docs/current/static/libpq-pgpass.html&quot;&gt;file&lt;/a&gt; that is providing the password for you? Do you have &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;$PGPASSWORD&lt;/code&gt; defined in your &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.postgresql.org/docs/current/static/libpq-envars.html&quot;&gt;environment&lt;/a&gt;? Fix the password being passed to PostgreSQL, and you won’t have further issues in this scenario.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;scenario-2---pg_hbaconf-rejects-you&quot;&gt;Scenario 2 - pg_hba.conf rejects you&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For our second scenario, we’re going to assume that you &lt;em&gt;can&lt;/em&gt; actually connect to the PostgreSQL instance, but there is an entry in &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;pg_hba.conf&lt;/code&gt; denying you access. First, we’ll try connecting via a local Unix socket:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/reject_socket.png&quot; alt=&quot;reject socket&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you can see, it straight up tells you that you have been &lt;em&gt;explicitly denied access&lt;/em&gt;. It may be rejecting connections via Unix sockets completely, or it may be rejecting connection as the specified user via Unix socket, or it may be rejecting connections to the specified database via Unix sock. You could determine which of these scenarios is true by trying a different user on the same database and then trying the same user on a different database. In any case, the problem &lt;em&gt;is not&lt;/em&gt; networking or firewall related. The DBA needs to adjust &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;pg_hba.conf&lt;/code&gt; to allow connections of this type, or you need to connect via a TCP port instead of a Unix socket. Discuss with your DBA.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, let’s try via a TCP port:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/reject_port.png&quot; alt=&quot;reject port&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again, you can see that it pretty plainly tells you that you have been &lt;em&gt;explicitly denied&lt;/em&gt;. In this case though, it may be rejecting your IP address specifically, your entire network segment, your id, that database, or the fact that you didn’t make an SSL connection. You can whittle this down by trying a different user on the same db, trying the same user on a different db, or switching to an SSL connection and repeating these tests. (I assume that you can’t change your IP address. But perhaps you could make the same test cases from another computer). Again, you’ll probably need the DBA to resolve this with you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;scenario-3---pg_hbaconf-doesnt-allow-you&quot;&gt;Scenario 3 - pg_hba.conf doesn’t allow you&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know what you’re thinking. “Isn’t this the same as above?”. And the answer is “no it is not”. Above, the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;pg_hba.conf&lt;/code&gt; file had an entry that matched your incoming connection and said to &lt;strong&gt;explicitly&lt;/strong&gt; reject it. In this scenario, there is &lt;em&gt;no entry that matches your connection&lt;/em&gt; and you end up &lt;strong&gt;implicitly&lt;/strong&gt; denied.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again, we’ll start by using a Unix socket:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/noentry_socket.png&quot; alt=&quot;no entry socket&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once more, the message pretty clearly tells you what is wrong. As it says, &lt;em&gt;there is no entry in &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;pg_hba.conf&lt;/code&gt; that matches your incoming connection&lt;/em&gt;. And since PostgreSQL tries to err on the side of caution, when it can’t find an entry stating definitively what to do, it rejects you. The same troubleshooting steps as above apply (change the user/db, etc). And also like above, the DBA is going to need to edit &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;pg_hba.conf&lt;/code&gt; to add an entry for your connection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, what does it look like over a TCP port:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/noentry_port.png&quot; alt=&quot;no entry port&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s the same error message as above but showing your IP address instead of &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;[local]&lt;/code&gt;. And the same debugging applies. Once again, the DBA will need to add an entry to &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;pg_hba.conf&lt;/code&gt; to resolve this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;scenario-4---everything-else-no-really&quot;&gt;Scenario 4 - everything else (no, really)&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By default, PostgreSQL listens for connections on port 5432. Sometimes, your DBA (or your vendor) has chosen to run PostgreSQL on a different port for some reason. If you are not trying to connect to the correct port, you’ll get an error from &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;psql&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you were trying to connect via a Unix socket, you’ll see:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/socket_nope.png&quot; alt=&quot;socket nope&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you were trying a TCP port connection, you’d see:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/port_nope.png&quot; alt=&quot;port nope&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This error indicates that it cannot establish a network connection with PostgreSQL at the IP address (or UNix socket) you specified on the default port. Check to make sure you don’t have &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;$PGPORT&lt;/code&gt; set incorrectly in your environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you &lt;em&gt;are&lt;/em&gt; using the correct port, and you still see one of two errors above, then the issue will be one of the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;PostgreSQL isn’t running&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;PostgreSQL is running, but on a different IP address than you’re trying to connect to&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;PostgreSQL is running, but you cannot establish a network connection from here to there&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If PostgreSQL isn’t running, talk to your DBA about why (maybe it died, maybe it’s a maintenance window). If you are affected by the 2&lt;sup&gt;nd&lt;/sup&gt; bullet item, you’ll have to talk with your DBA about the proper IP address to use when connecting. And if you’re plagued by the 3&lt;sup&gt;rd&lt;/sup&gt; bullet item, you’ll have to talk to your network admin (and probably your DBA) as there may be a firewall blocking you, or your VLAN can’t connect to the other VLAN, or some other layer 3/4 tomfoolery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So now you know all the (common) ways that connecting to PostgreSQL can fail and how to distinguish between them. With just a little bit of knowledge, you can communicate exactly what is happening to your DBA and make it easier for him/her to rectify the issue. Go forth, and happy PostgreSQL-ing.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    <link>/posts/When-you-cannot-get-there-from-here/ </link>
    <pubDate>2017-07-25T07:42:47-04:00</pubDate>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">/posts/When-you-cannot-get-there-from-here/</guid>
   </item>
  
   <item>
    <title>Goodbye, Loui boy</title>
    <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/loui.jpg&quot; class=&quot;rleader&quot; /&gt;Thank you, Loui, for bringing so much joy and happiness to our lives these past ten years. &lt;em&gt;I will miss you.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
    <link>/posts/Goodbye-Loui-boy/ </link>
    <pubDate>2017-02-16T03:35:19-05:00</pubDate>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">/posts/Goodbye-Loui-boy/</guid>
   </item>
  
   <item>
    <title>Changes to the blog</title>
    <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;rleader&quot; src=&quot;http://www.cafecowboys.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/blogging-inside.gif&quot; /&gt;In case you haven’t already noticed, I’ve made some changes to my blog recently. Nothing really significant or drastic, but things that have been on the TODO list for a while.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I guess the most obvious change would be that I added pagination finally. If you scroll the homepage all the way down, instead of it going back through the entire blog’s history, it stops after five posts, and then gives a clickable page counter. Once I had this implemented, I then had to un-paginate the archive pages which was interesting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next most visible change would probably be the change I made to the CSS concerning CODE and CODEBLOCK. I’m still not 100% sure this is the final form, but I like it better than it was. For reference, it now looks like &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;this&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My third change was to tweak the site’s header a bit. If you cast your gaze upwards, you can see that I now have ‘About’, ‘Archive’, and ‘Feeds’ in the header. The ‘Feeds’ link is new, as is the page that it links to. The actual RSS feeds themselves have existed for a while now, I just didn’t announce them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And finally, I swapped out my photo for my new Bitmoji-based avatar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, uh, enjoy. Or something.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    <link>/posts/changes-to-the-blog/ </link>
    <pubDate>2016-12-02T08:48:42-05:00</pubDate>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">/posts/changes-to-the-blog/</guid>
   </item>
  
   <item>
    <title>Welcome to Cypheri</title>
    <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.nationstates.net/images/flags/uploads/cypheri__561515.jpg&quot; class=&quot;lleader&quot; /&gt;I recently discovered the online game &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nationstates.net&quot;&gt;NationStates&lt;/a&gt; thanks to a Reddit thread and was intrigued. So I logged in, created the nation of Cypheri and then used &lt;a href=&quot;https://blogtrottr.com&quot;&gt;BlogTrottr&lt;/a&gt; to feed the RSS feed into my inbox (which allows me offline play essentially. I ignore it until I get a notice). So far, it’s been a neat little experience. I’m pretty sure if you know me well enough to be reading this blog that I know you well enough to say you’ll enjoy it too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Without further ado, let me welcome you to the Republic of Cypheri, a left-leaning college state. Our motto is “strength through freedom”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Republic of Cypheri is a tiny, genial nation, renowned for its compulsory military service and irreverence towards religion. The compassionate population of 7 million Cypherians enjoy extensive civil freedoms, particularly in social issues, while business tends to be more regulated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The large government prioritizes Education, although Welfare, Defense, and Law &amp;amp; Order are also considered important, while Spirituality and Industry are ignored. The average income tax rate is 39.8%, but much higher for the wealthy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Cypherian economy, worth 251 billion dollars a year, is fairly diversified and led by the Tourism industry, with major contributions from Automobile Manufacturing, Basket Weaving, and Retail. State-owned companies are common. Average income is 35,928 dollars, and evenly distributed, with the richest citizens earning only 2.0 times as much as the poorest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for visiting, we hope you enjoyed your time here!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    <link>/posts/Welcome-to-Cypheri/ </link>
    <pubDate>2016-10-01T07:23:56-04:00</pubDate>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">/posts/Welcome-to-Cypheri/</guid>
   </item>
  
   <item>
    <title>Functional Blog Archives</title>
    <description>&lt;p&gt;After an afternoon dicking around with Jekyll templates and Google serching, I’ve fixed up this site’s archive pages and tag cloud pages. I now have functional archive pages for everything, each year, each month of said year, and each day of said month. And they should all continue to function perfectly well on their own as time progresses (unless I bork something up later trying to be clever). I’ve also modified the tag cloud page to fit in the archive pages’ look an feel. It’s not a true tag cloud in that I don’t increae the weight or height of the font based on frequency, but the cloud does contain every tag used across the blog and each tag has it’s own page showing all posts tagged as such.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, yeah. Enjoy, or something.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    <link>/posts/Functional-Blog-Archives/ </link>
    <pubDate>2016-09-30T19:30:19-04:00</pubDate>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">/posts/Functional-Blog-Archives/</guid>
   </item>
  
   <item>
    <title>Making use of gists</title>
    <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-5yjV3rrAvHk/U6Gm4-prTPI/AAAAAAAAJf4/7HXcjGxXGxI/s1600/logo_github_gist.png&quot; class=&quot;rleader&quot; /&gt; After stumbling upon an example of how to do so, I’ve converted all my existing blog posts to use GitHub Gists instead of inline code blocks. It gives me added functionality, and reduces the size of the blog pages as well. Might as well use every GitHub feature I can since I’ve chosen that platform for hosting my blog, right? :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    <link>/posts/Making-use-of-gists/ </link>
    <pubDate>2016-06-19T11:42:19-04:00</pubDate>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">/posts/Making-use-of-gists/</guid>
   </item>
  
   <item>
    <title>Hello, eero</title>
    <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eero.com&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://iotlist-production.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/uploads/production/post_attachment/937/file/Eero1.jpg&quot; class=&quot;lleader&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;I don’t normally back things on Indiegogo (I’m a Kickstarter snob), but I jumped &lt;em&gt;all over&lt;/em&gt; the eero. I have always had issues with the wifi coverage in my home. I’ve tried everything I can think of to alleviate the issues; differernt brands of routers, flashing different OSS firmwares, ‘upgrading’ to SOHO equipment instead of consumer equipment, moving them all over the damn house, etc. Nothing solved all the issues. Until now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve actully had the eero up and running for a while now (almost two months already) but I held off saying anything because I wanted to see if issues would crop back up or not and I wanted to get past the initial ‘cool, it works!’ feeling. So here I am ~60 days later, and I’m &lt;em&gt;still&lt;/em&gt; feeling the ‘this is cool’ feeling towards the eero.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I bought the triple set, put the ‘main’ one in the basement by the cable modem, the next one on the other end of the house on the first floor, and the final one in the middle of the house on the second floor. Setup was stupid simple and hassle free. Like, Tina or Emily could have done this, simple. Once up and talking to each other, they then scanned all the wifi leakage from the neighbors and picked a channel with the least amount of interference and started handing out DHCP leases to my devices. Easy peasy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaking of ‘my devices’.. here’s everything I’ve got hooked up to the eero-powered wifi:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 x Nest thermostat&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 x “smart” tv&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 x “smart” bluray player&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 x Nexus Player /  Android TV&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 x PS3&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 x PS4&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 x Sonos speaker&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 x Macbook Pro&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 x Android phones&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;3 x Android tablets&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 x iPhone&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 x iPad mini&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 x Chromebook&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 x Lenovo laptop&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, I didn’t make that list to impress you, or to depress myself at how much money I’ve spent over the years. That list is to show what’s connected to the eero and to show that there is a big variety of devices. Some are 2.4GHz, some 5GHz, some both. Some do jumbo frames. Some support wifi media extensions. And they all work &lt;em&gt;flawlessly&lt;/em&gt; while connected to the eero. &lt;em&gt;No matter how many are connected simultaneoussly.&lt;/em&gt; Which is the first time ever. Seriously. It works so well, I went around and &lt;em&gt;unplugged&lt;/em&gt; Ethernet from devices that had it and put them on the wifi!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We can have multiple Netflix streams going while playing online in an FPS while streaming music to another room while someone else is on the laptop working. And no one even notices the other users. It’s epic. I now actually have a valid reason for buying the most expensive upload speed my ISP offers :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for gripes? Well, of course no system is perfect. In its quest to make things stupid simple, there’s a lot the eero mgmt app doesn’t let you do. You can’t, for example, blacklist a MAC. Or turn off uplink for certain MACs between certain hours of the day. You can’t throttle certain devices. Basically, all the things nerds love to mess with that just confuse the normal consumer. And I’m (mostly) OK with that. I’m sure some of the functionality is coming in future updates, but even if it doesn’t, I don’t care. It just works. And it works well and easy enough that I can talk the wife through an issue over the phone while I’m on the other side of the planet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I &amp;lt;3 my eero.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;★★★★★&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    <link>/posts/Hello_eero/ </link>
    <pubDate>2016-03-30T10:00:25-04:00</pubDate>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">/posts/Hello_eero/</guid>
   </item>
  
   <item>
    <title>Flyover State</title>
    <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://howmuch.net/content/images/1600/cost-of-driving-from-Columbus-49c5.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://howmuch.net/content/images/1600/cost-of-driving-from-Columbus-49c5.png&quot; class=&quot;lleader&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;Being a native of Ohio, I can assure you that I’ve heard every form of ‘flyover state’ insult you could care to level at me. And while I won’t debate the merits of Ohio in this post, I will take a minute to point out something that I’ve been saying for quite some time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ohio really is pretty centrally located to anywhere you might care to be other than the left coast.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The map I’ve linked to in this post shows what $50 worth of gas means to someone from Columbus, OH as far as their ability to drive anywhere. Of course, it makes an assumption about the price of gas and the car’s mpg (24mpg, iirc) but the point stands.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And this is what I’ve been telling my coworker a lot lately. I travel periodically for business, and whenever I do, I &lt;strong&gt;drive&lt;/strong&gt; (unless it’s just way too impractical). It &lt;em&gt;alway&lt;/em&gt; trips people out when I do. I’d much rather grab a rental car, and spend a day on my own schedule seeing the country then being crammed in like cattle and dealing with the TSA. And this image shows that I’m generally saving the company money as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, you all can keep flying over. In the meantime, I’ll be driving around enjoying myself,&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    <link>/posts/Flyover-state/ </link>
    <pubDate>2016-02-09T11:59:24-05:00</pubDate>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">/posts/Flyover-state/</guid>
   </item>
  
   <item>
    <title>Efficient, yet Creepy</title>
    <description>&lt;p&gt;So I’m sitting here seting up a new Internet connected device I bought recently (more on it later) and I can’t seem to get it to setup properly. I can create an account on their site, I can login to said account, I can power on said device and connect to it using the app and configure it to use my home wifi, but the device just won’t ever finish connecting and syncing w/ my account on the site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I try this about half a dozen times, with a few reboots and even a reset of the device in there. Still no luck. So I power it off, set it aside, and go do some things IRL thinking “I’ll come back to it”. Not five minutes later, I get an email on my phone from Tech Support at the device’s company saying thusly:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;We noticed that you are having problems adding $device to your system.
To assist you with the process, we would like to first push a firmware
update to your $device. Please keep your $device plugged in and we
will take care of the rest. We will send you another email when you
have been updated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now &lt;em&gt;that’s&lt;/em&gt; efficient. And &lt;strong&gt;super creepy&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I kinda like it :D&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    <link>/posts/Efficient-Yet-Creepy/ </link>
    <pubDate>2016-01-21T13:30:00-05:00</pubDate>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">/posts/Efficient-Yet-Creepy/</guid>
   </item>
  
 </channel>
</rss>
