<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>General on Doug&#39;s Dabblings | Quick thoughts on stuff I&#39;m playing with</title>
    <link>https://hunleyd.github.io/categories/general/</link>
    <description>Recent content in General on Doug&#39;s Dabblings | Quick thoughts on stuff I&#39;m playing with</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Feb 2019 07:24:43 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://hunleyd.github.io/categories/general/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The continuing adventures of Mom cutting the cord</title>
      <link>https://hunleyd.github.io/posts/the-continuing-adventures-of-mom-cutting-the-cord/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Feb 2019 07:24:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hunleyd.github.io/posts/the-continuing-adventures-of-mom-cutting-the-cord/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As a belated update to &lt;a href=&#34;https://hunleyd.github.io/posts/Mom-cuts-the-cord/&#34;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; post, Mom has told DirecTV to completely go screw and she’s moved over to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.philo.com&#34;&gt;Philo&lt;/a&gt; where she’s currently loving life.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mom cuts the cord</title>
      <link>https://hunleyd.github.io/posts/mom-cuts-the-cord/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 May 2018 11:12:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hunleyd.github.io/posts/mom-cuts-the-cord/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;OK folks, it finally happened. My mother has cut the cord and now gets all her TV needs satisfied via OTA and OTT. Yes, you heard right. My mother. The same woman who spent the better part of a decade (I cut the cord in late 2008) saying how she didn&amp;rsquo;t understand how I could not have cable. Someone check the temperature in Hell will ya? :)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Car(e) free in Columbus</title>
      <link>https://hunleyd.github.io/posts/car-free-in-columbus/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2018 15:55:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hunleyd.github.io/posts/car-free-in-columbus/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last year, at the beginning of March, I turned in my &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.autoguide.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2013/09/2014-kia-optima.jpg&#34;&gt;2014 Kia Optima LX&lt;/a&gt; at the end of its lease and decided to go &amp;lsquo;car free&amp;rsquo;. I wanted to see exactly how much of a PITA it would be, how many services I&amp;rsquo;d need to subscribe to to get things done, and how much money it would actually save me. It&amp;rsquo;s now been a year, and I can definitively answer these questions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Goodbye, Loui boy</title>
      <link>https://hunleyd.github.io/posts/goodbye-loui-boy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2017 08:35:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hunleyd.github.io/posts/goodbye-loui-boy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hunleyd.github.io/images/posts/loui.jpg&#34; class=&#34;rleader&#34;&gt;Thank you, Loui, for bringing so much joy and happiness to our lives these past ten years. &lt;em&gt;I will miss you.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to Cypheri</title>
      <link>https://hunleyd.github.io/posts/welcome-to-cypheri/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2016 11:23:56 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hunleyd.github.io/posts/welcome-to-cypheri/</guid>
      <description>&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.nationstates.net/images/flags/uploads/cypheri__755901.jpg&#34; class=&#34;lleader&#34; /&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I recently discovered the online game &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nationstates.net&#34;&gt;NationStates&lt;/a&gt; thanks to a Reddit thread and was intrigued. So I logged in, created the nation of Cypheri and then used &lt;a href=&#34;https://blogtrottr.com&#34;&gt;BlogTrottr&lt;/a&gt; to feed the RSS feed into my inbox (which allows me offline play essentially. I ignore it until I get a notice). So far, it&amp;rsquo;s been a neat little experience. I&amp;rsquo;m pretty sure if you know me well enough to be reading this blog that I know you well enough to say you&amp;rsquo;ll enjoy it too.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Functional Blog Archives</title>
      <link>https://hunleyd.github.io/posts/functional-blog-archives/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2016 23:30:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hunleyd.github.io/posts/functional-blog-archives/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After an afternoon dicking around with Jekyll templates and Google searching, I&amp;rsquo;ve fixed up this site&amp;rsquo;s archive pages and tag cloud pages. I now have functional archive pages for everything, each year, each month of said year, and each day of said month. And they should all continue to function perfectly well on their own as time progresses (unless I bork something up later trying to be clever). I&amp;rsquo;ve also modified the tag cloud page to fit in the archive pages&amp;rsquo; look an feel. It&amp;rsquo;s not a true tag cloud in that I don&amp;rsquo;t increase the weight or height of the font based on frequency, but the cloud does contain every tag used across the blog and each tag has it&amp;rsquo;s own page showing all posts tagged as such.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Making use of gists</title>
      <link>https://hunleyd.github.io/posts/making-use-of-gists/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jun 2016 15:42:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hunleyd.github.io/posts/making-use-of-gists/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-5yjV3rrAvHk/U6Gm4-prTPI/AAAAAAAAJf4/7HXcjGxXGxI/s1600/logo_github_gist.png&#34; class=&#34;rleader&#34; /&gt; After stumbling upon an example of how to do so, I&amp;rsquo;ve converted all my existing blog posts to use GitHub Gists instead of inline code blocks. It gives me added functionality, and reduces the size of the blog pages as well. Might as well use every GitHub feature I can since I&amp;rsquo;ve chosen that platform for hosting my blog, right? :)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hello, eero</title>
      <link>https://hunleyd.github.io/posts/hello_eero/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2016 14:00:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hunleyd.github.io/posts/hello_eero/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.eero.com&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://d2vw57jh8139vw.cloudfront.net/abb56b35841139f06625b173a8bb8936.jpg&#34; class=&#34;lleader&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t normally back things on Indiegogo (I&amp;rsquo;m a Kickstarter snob), but I jumped &lt;em&gt;all over&lt;/em&gt; the eero. I have always had issues with the wifi coverage in my home. I&amp;rsquo;ve tried everything I can think of to alleviate the issues; differernt brands of routers, flashing different OSS firmwares, &amp;lsquo;upgrading&amp;rsquo; to SOHO equipment instead of consumer equipment, moving them all over the damn house, etc. Nothing solved all the issues. Until now.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Flyover State</title>
      <link>https://hunleyd.github.io/posts/flyover-state/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2016 16:59:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hunleyd.github.io/posts/flyover-state/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://howmuch.net/content/images/1600/cost-of-driving-from-Columbus-49c5.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://howmuch.net/content/images/1600/cost-of-driving-from-Columbus-49c5.png&#34; class=&#34;lleader&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Being a native of Ohio, I can assure you that I&amp;rsquo;ve heard every form of &amp;lsquo;flyover state&amp;rsquo; insult you could care to level at me. And while I won&amp;rsquo;t debate the merits of Ohio in this post, I will take a minute to point out something that I&amp;rsquo;ve been saying for quite some time.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Efficient, yet Creepy</title>
      <link>https://hunleyd.github.io/posts/efficient-yet-creepy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2016 18:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hunleyd.github.io/posts/efficient-yet-creepy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So I&amp;rsquo;m sitting here seting up a new Internet connected device I bought recently (more on it later) and I can&amp;rsquo;t seem to get it to setup properly. I can create an account on their site, I can login to said account, I can power on said device and connect to it using the app and configure it to use my home wifi, but the device just won&amp;rsquo;t ever finish connecting and syncing w/ my account on the site.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
