<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Productivity on Doug&#39;s Dabblings | Quick thoughts on stuff I&#39;m playing with</title>
    <link>https://hunleyd.github.io/tags/productivity/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Productivity on Doug&#39;s Dabblings | Quick thoughts on stuff I&#39;m playing with</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 25 Mar 2023 17:23:08 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://hunleyd.github.io/tags/productivity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Meetings, menu bars, and focus modes</title>
      <link>https://hunleyd.github.io/posts/meetings--menu-bars--and-focus-modes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Mar 2023 17:23:08 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hunleyd.github.io/posts/meetings--menu-bars--and-focus-modes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We recently moved all our issue tracking at work from &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com&#34;&gt;GitHub Issues&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&#34;https://linear.app&#34;&gt;Linear&lt;/a&gt; for one of the products that I work on. While playing around with Linear, I stumbled upon their &lt;a href=&#34;https://reclaim.ai&#34;&gt;Reclaim.AI&lt;/a&gt; integration and immediately fell in love. I quickly set about connecting the two tools, tweaking my settings, and even opened some issues w/ the Support teams of both products. After about a week, I finally had everything up and running exactly how I wanted it. During our sprint planning meeting, I simply pulled whatever Linear issues I wanted to work on into the cycle, and then let Reclaim schedule my work based on priority and points. While I could probably write an entire blog post about these two apps, these tools are really just the &amp;lsquo;setting&amp;rsquo; for this post. You see, now that I had all my work being scheduled for me by a AI, I found that I needed to have my calendar open at all times to see what I was supposed to be working on. I &lt;em&gt;hate&lt;/em&gt; having apps open (or extra tabs in a browser) when I can have the info presented to me in some other fashion. Thankfully, I had previously discovered &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/leits/MeetingBar&#34;&gt;MeetingBar&lt;/a&gt; and was already a huge fan. So now I have MeetingBar running in my OSX menu bar showing me (via Reclaim) exactly what I&amp;rsquo;m supposed to be working on (or what I&amp;rsquo;m about to start working on). I was living the dream.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
